<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ChaoNEil</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ChaoNEil</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 11:45:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Malware Traffic Analysis (My thought Process)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/malware-traffic-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 11:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/malware-traffic-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Hello blue teamers, this is my first traffic analysis writeup for my future reference and also to document my self-learning journey in Cyber Security, so I will keep this short and simple while going through how i approached this Wireshark network packet capture (pcap) file.&#xA;(Remember , through this write-up, i am talking to me, my future self. If any random people reads it, forgive me for any mistakes. Enjoy! )</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-blog/</guid>
      <description>This will be the place where I put all of my blogs of stuff that I find interesting. It might not be interesting to you. It will be mostly blue team related content or anything that I find cool.&#xA;I have some blogs already written. I will upload them here, stay tuned.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Heartbreaker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/heartbreaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/heartbreaker/</guid>
      <description>Sherlocks - Medium Sherlock Scenario&#xA;Delicate situation alert! The customer has just been alerted about concerning reports indicating a potential breach of their database, with information allegedly being circulated on the darknet market. As the Incident Responder, it&amp;rsquo;s your responsibility to get to the bottom of it. Your task is to conduct an investigation into an email received by one of their employees, comprehending the implications, and uncovering any possible connections to the data breach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Knock-Knock</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/knock-knock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/knock-knock/</guid>
      <description>Sherlocks - Medium Sherlock Scenario&#xA;A critical Forela Dev server was targeted by a threat group. The Dev server was accidentally left open to the internet which it was not supposed to be. The senior dev Abdullah told the IT team that the server was fully hardened and it&amp;rsquo;s still difficult to comprehend how the attack took place and how the attacker got access in the first place. Forela recently started its business expansion in Pakistan and Abdullah was the one IN charge of all infrastructure deployment and management.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Kuber</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kuber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kuber/</guid>
      <description>Sherlocks - Easy Sherlock Scenario&#xA;As a digital forensics investigator, you received an urgent request from a client managing multiple proxy Kubernetes clusters. The client reports unusual behavior in one of their development environments, where they were testing a proxy via SSH. This environment was exposed to the internet, raising concerns about a potential security breach. You have been provided with a dump of the kube-system namespace, as most of the testing activity occurred there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB NeuroSync-D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/htb-sherlock-neurosync/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/htb-sherlock-neurosync/</guid>
      <description>Sherlocks - Easy Sherlock Scenario&#xA;NeuroSync™ is a leading suite of products focusing on developing cutting edge medical BCI devices, designed by the Korosaki Coorporaton. Recently, an APT group targeted them and was able to infiltrate their infrastructure and is now moving laterally to compromise more systems. It appears that they have even managed to hijack a large number of online devices by exploiting an N-day vulnerability. Your task is to find out how they were able to compromise the infrastructure and understand how to secure it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Pikaptcha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pipkapcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pipkapcha/</guid>
      <description>Sherlocks - Easy Sherlock Scenario&#xA;Happy Grunwald contacted the sysadmin, Alonzo, because of issues he had downloading the latest version of Microsoft Office. He had received an email saying he needed to update, and clicked the link to do it. He reported that he visited the website and solved a captcha, but no office download page came back. Alonzo, who himself was bombarded with phishing attacks last year and was now aware of attacker tactics, immediately notified the security team to isolate the machine as he suspected an attack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reverse-engineer-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reverse-engineer-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>These are all notes I took while learning reverse engineering (still a work in progress). I plan to complement them with further research, including videos and other resources. This is very uncharted territory for me so bear with me.&#xA;RE theory&#xA;When you compile a binary in C , what happens ? gcc myProgram.c -o myProgram.exe&#xA;It goes through these 4 stages , this is called Language Processing System.&#xA;(Preprocessor &amp;mdash;&amp;gt; Compiler &amp;mdash;&amp;gt; Assembler &amp;mdash;&amp;gt; Linker ) &amp;mdash;-&amp;gt; myProgram.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOAR EDR Cloud Project (LimaCharlie and Tines)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/soc-lab2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/soc-lab2/</guid>
      <description>Integration of SOAR and EDR featuring LimaCharlie and Tines. Learning how to automate security workflows, and enhancing cybersecurity posture effectively.&#xA;For VMs, I will be using Vultr cloud resources again. I have spun a windows 10 machine with firewalls configured to RDP only from my public IP.&#xA;Project Main Takeaways: Creating custom detection &amp;amp; response rule in LimaCharlie&#xD;Creating a playbook that integrates Slack, Tines, Email.&#xD;Playbook contents:&#xD;1. Send a Slack message&#xD;2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOC Active Directory Cloud Project (Splunk, Shuffle and Slack)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/soc-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/soc-lab/</guid>
      <description>Logical Diagram / Setup Structure CompanyX-ADDC01 ip 139.x.x.x public&#xD;CompanyX-ADDC01 ip 10.51.96.4 private&#xD;Test instance ip 139.x.x.x public&#xD;Test instance&#x9;ip 10.51.96.3 private&#xD;CompanyX-Splunk ip 139.x.x.x public&#xD;CompanyX-Splunk ip 10.51.96.5 private Using Vultr cloud resources , I set up 3 different machines:&#xA;1 splunk ubuntu machine that will be the splunk server&#xD;1 Active directory machine 1 test windows machine&#xD;I have set up a VPC network so that all 3 machines could interact nicely.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whoami</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/whoami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/whoami/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I am Chao Neil Aryan Borgohain and I&amp;rsquo;m just a n00b trying to be a cyber security analyst.&#xA;Currently I have the Google Cybersecurity certificate and I&amp;rsquo;m working on my Sec+ certificate, also, at the same time following the HackTheBox CDSA (SOC) job path. I have also set up home labs to practice attacks and defense and analyse malwares.&#xA;Things that I am interested:&#xA;Malware Analysis Malware Development &amp;hellip;some rev engineering I can&amp;rsquo;t put my whole cybersecurity origin story here, so if you want to know more, there should be a link here somewhere</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
