<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ChaoNEil</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ChaoNEil</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 11:45:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Malware Traffic Analysis (My thought Process)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/malware-traffic-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 11:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/malware-traffic-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Hello blue teamers, this is my first traffic analysis writeup for my future reference and also to document my self-learning journey in Cyber Security, so I will keep this short and simple while going through how i approached this Wireshark network packet capture (pcap) file.&#xA;(Remember , through this write-up, i am talking to me, my future self. If any random people reads it, forgive me for any mistakes. Enjoy! )</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-blog/</guid>
      <description>This will be the place where I put all of my blogs of stuff that I find interesting. It might not be interesting to you. It will be mostly blue team related content or anything that I find cool.&#xA;I have some blogs already written. I will upload them here, stay tuned.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB NeuroSync-D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/htb-sherlock-neurosync/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/htb-sherlock-neurosync/</guid>
      <description>Sherlocks - Easy Sherlock Scenario&#xA;NeuroSync™ is a leading suite of products focusing on developing cutting edge medical BCI devices, designed by the Korosaki Coorporaton. Recently, an APT group targeted them and was able to infiltrate their infrastructure and is now moving laterally to compromise more systems. It appears that they have even managed to hijack a large number of online devices by exploiting an N-day vulnerability. Your task is to find out how they were able to compromise the infrastructure and understand how to secure it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whoami</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/whoami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/whoami/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I am Chao Neil Aryan Borgohain and I&amp;rsquo;m just a n00b trying to be a cyber security analyst.&#xA;Currently I have the Google Cybersecurity certificate and I&amp;rsquo;m working on my Sec+ certificate, also, at the same time following the HackTheBox CDSA (SOC) job path. I have also set up home labs to practice attacks and defense and analyse malwares.&#xA;Things that I am interested:&#xA;Malware Analysis Malware Development &amp;hellip;some rev engineering I can&amp;rsquo;t put my whole cybersecurity origin story here, so if you want to know more, there should be a link here somewhere</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
